.
Thank you.
Yes.
God, be gracious and merciful to me, the sinner.
Blessed is our God, always, now and forever,
and
to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Glory to you, our God.
Glory to you.
Heavenly King, Comforter, Spirit of Truth,
present in all places and filling all things.
Treasury of good things and giver of life,
come, take your about in us.
Cleanse us of every stain
and save our souls, O good one.
Amen.
Holy God, holy mighty, holy mortal, have mercy on us.
Thank you.
Glory to the Father, to the Son, to the Holy Spirit,
both now and ever into the ages of ages. Amen.
All Holy Trinity have mercy on us.
Lord, forgive our sins. Master, pardon our transgressions.
Holy One, visit and heal our infirmities for your name's sake.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, to the Holy Spirit,
both now and ever into the ages of ages. Amen.
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done, on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us of our trespasses,
as we forgive those.
trespass against us and lead us not into temptation but deliver us from evil for
thine is the kingdom the power and the glory of the Father and of the Son and
of the Holy Spirit now and forever and to the ages of ages
save O Lord your people and bless your inheritance granting victory to the
faithful over the enemy and by your cross protecting your commonwealth glory
to the Father and to the Son to the Holy Spirit you who were lifted on the cross
voluntarily, O Christ our God, bestow your attention.
their compassions upon your new community to which
you gave your name. Cause our faithful
emperors to be glad in your power, granting
them victories against their adversaries,
and for an ally, Lord, may they have you.
Peace is their armor, trophy invisible.
Both now and ever into the ages of ages.
Amen. O awesome and unashamed
will protection. O good and praiseworthy
Theotokos, do not despise our petitions.
Make firm the community of the Orthodox.
Save those whom you have called to rule.
Grant them victory from heaven, for you gave
birth to God and are truly blessed.
have mercy on us
so
God, according to your great mercy,
we pray to you, hear us and have mercy.
Let us pray for mercy, Lord of mercy, Lord of mercy.
Let us pray for pious and Orthodox Christians.
Again, we pray for our Father and Archbishop Nicholas
and all our brotherhood in Christ.
Let us pray for mercy, Lord of mercy, Lord of mercy.
For you are a merciful God who loves mankind,
and to you we offer up glory to the Father.
and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
In the name of the Lord, Father, bless.
Glory to the holy, consubstantial,
life-giving and undivided Trinity,
always, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Glory to God in the highest and on earth,
peace, goodwill among men.
Peace.
goodwill among men. O Lord, you shall open my lips and my mouth will declare your praise. O Lord,
you shall open my lips and my mouth will declare your praise. O Lord, why do those who afflict me
multiply? Many are those who rise up against me. Many are those who say to my soul, there is no
salvation for him and his God. But you, O Lord, are my protector, my glory, and the one who lifts
up my head. I cried to the Lord with my voice and he heard me from his holy hill. I lay down and
slept and I awoke for the Lord will help me. I will not be afraid of ten thousands of people who
who set themselves against me all around.
Arise, O Lord, and save me, O my God, for you struck all those who were at foolishly at an enmity with me.
You broke the teeth of sinners. Salvation is of the Lord, and your blessing is upon your people.
I lay down and slept, and I awoke, for the Lord will help me.
O Lord, do not rebuke me in your wrath, nor chase me in your anger.
For your arrows are fixed in me, and your hand rests on me.
There is no healing in my flesh because of your wrath.
There is no peace in my bones because of my sins.
For my transgressions rise up over my head.
they're like a heavy burden, they're heavy on me.
My wounds grow foul and fester because of my folly.
I suffer misery and I am utterly bowed down.
I go all the day long with a sad face, for my loins are filled with mockeries,
and there is no healing in my flesh.
I am afflicted and greatly humbled.
I roar because of the groaning in my heart.
O Lord, all my desire is before you, and my groaning is not hidden from you.
My heart is troubled, my strength fails me,
and the light of my eyes even this is not with me.
My friends and neighbors draw near and stand against me,
and my nearer can stand far off.
and those who seek my soul.
use violence, and those who seek evil from me speak folly, and they meditate on deceit
all the day long.
But I, like a deaf man, do not hear, and I am like a mute who does not open his mouth.
I am like a man who does not hear and who has no reproofs in his mouth.
For in you, O Lord, I hope you will hear, O Lord my God.
For I said, Let not my enemies rejoice over me.
For when my foot was shaken, they boasted against me.
For I am ready for wounds, and my pain is continually with me.
For I will declare my transgression, and I will be anxious about my sin.
where my enemies live.
and are become stronger than I.
And those who hate me unjustly are multiplied,
and those who repaid me evil for good slandered me
because I pursue righteousness.
And they threw away my love as though it were a stinking corpse.
Do not forsake me, O Lord, O my God.
Do not depart from me.
Give heed to help me, O Lord, of my salvation.
Do not forsake me, O Lord, O my God.
Do not depart from me.
Give heed to help me, O Lord, of my salvation.
O God, my God, I rise up early to be with you.
My soul thirsts for you.
How often my flesh thirsts for you
in a desolate, impassable, and waterless land.
So in the holy place I appear before you to see your power and your glory because your mercy is better than life.
My lips shall praise you. Thus I will bless you in my life.
I will lift up my hands in your name.
May my soul be filled as with marrow and fatness and my mouth shall sing your praise to you with lips filled with rejoicing.
If I remembered you on my bed, I meditated on you at daybreak.
For you are my helper and in the shelter of your wings I will greatly rejoice.
My soul follows close behind you. Your right hand takes hold of me.
but they seek for my soul in vain.
They shall go into the lowest pits of the earth.
They shall be given over to the edge of the sword.
They shall be a portion for foxes, but the king shall be glad in God.
All who swear by him shall be praised,
for the mouth that speaks unrighteous things is stopped.
I meditated on you at daybreak, for you are my helper,
and in the shelter of your wings I will greatly rejoice.
My soul follows close behind you.
Your right hand takes hold of me.
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit,
both now and ever, and to the ages of ages. Amen.
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia.
Glory to you, O God.
Hallelujah, hallelujah.
Alleluia, alleluia. Glory to you, O God.
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia. Glory to you, O God.
Lord of mercy, Lord of mercy, Lord of mercy.
Glory to the Father and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit,
both now and ever and to the ages of ages. Amen.
O Lord, God, in my salvation, I cry day and night before you.
Let my prayer come before you.
Incline your ear to my supplication, O Lord.
For my soul is filled with sorrows, and my soul draws near to Hades.
I am counted among those who go down to the pit.
I am like a helpless man, free among the dead,
like slain men thrown down when sleeping in a grave,
whom you remember no more.
but they are
removed from your hand. They laid me in the lowest pit in dark places and in the shadow of death.
Your wrath rested upon me. You brought all your billows over me. You removed my acquaintances
far from me. They made me an abomination among themselves. I was betrayed and did not go forth.
My eyes weakened from poverty. O Lord, I cried to you the whole day long. I spread out my hands to
you. Will you work wonders for the dead or will physicians raise them up and acknowledge you?
Shall anyone in the grave describe your mercy and your truth and destruction? Shall your wonders be
known in darkness and your righteousness in a forgotten
line. But I cried to you
oh Lord, and in the morning my prayer shall come near to you. Why, oh Lord, do you reject my soul
and turn away your face from me? I am pouring in troubles for my youth, but having
been exalted, I was humbled and brought into despair. Your fierce anger passed over me
and your tears greatly troubled me. They can pass me like water all the day long.
They surrounded me at once. You removed far from me neighbor and friend and my acquaintances
because of my misery. Oh Lord, God of my salvation, I cry day and night before you.
Let my prayer come before you. Incline your ear to my supplication, oh Lord.
bless the Lord
all my soul
everything within me. Bless his holy name. Bless the Lord, O my soul, and forget not all his rewards,
who is merciful to all your transgressions, who heals all your diseases, who redeems your life
from corruption, who crowns you with mercy and compassion, who satisfies your desire with good
things, and your youth is renewed like the eagles. The Lord shows mercies and judgment to all who are
wronged. He made known his ways to Moses and the things he willed to the sons of Israel.
The Lord is compassionate and merciful, slow to anger and abounding in mercy. He will not become
angry to the end, nor will he be wrathful forever. He did not deal with
Verse 12.
who fear him, and his righteousness upon children's children, to such as keep his covenant and
remember his commandments to do them. The Lord prepared his throne in heaven, and his kingdom
rules over all. Bless the Lord, all you his angels, mighty in strength who do his word,
so as to hear the voice of his words. Bless the Lord, all you his hosts, his ministers who do his
will. Bless the Lord, all his works, in all places of his dominion. Bless the Lord, O my soul.
In all places of his dominion, bless the Lord, O my soul. O Lord, hear my prayer and give ear to
my supplication in your truth.
answer me in your righteousness. Do not enter into judgment with your servant. For no one living
shall become righteous in your sight. For the enemy persecuted my soul. He humbled my life to the
ground. He caused me to dwell in dark places as one long dead. And my spirit was in anguish within
me. My heart was troubled within me. I remember the days of old and I meditated on all your works.
I meditated on the works of your hands. I spread out my hands to you. My soul thirsts for you like
a waterless land. Hear me speedily, O Lord. My spirit faints within me. Turn not your face from
me, lest I become like those who go down to the pit. Cause me to hear your mercy in the morning,
for I hope in you. Make me know, O Lord, the way and where I should walk, for I lift up my soul to
you. Deliver me from my enemies, O Lord, for to you I leave for refuge. Teach me to do your will,
for you are my God. Your good spirit shall guide me in the land of uprightness. For your name's
sake, O Lord, give me life. In your righteousness you shall bring my soul out of affliction.
In your mercy you shall destroy my enemies. You shall utterly destroy all who afflict my soul,
for I am your servant.
Answer me in righteousness.
O Lord, do not enter into judgment with your servant.
Answer me in righteousness, O Lord.
Do not enter into judgment with your servant.
Your spirit shall guide me in the land of uprightness.
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit,
both now and ever, and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia.
Glory to you, O God.
Our hope, O Lord, glory to you.
In peace, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For the peace from above, for the salvation of our souls,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For peace of the whole world,
for the stability of the holy churches of God,
and for the unity of all, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For this holy house and for those who enter it
with faith revered.
and the fear of God, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For pious and orthodox Christians,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our Father and Archbishop Nicholas,
the Honorable Presbyterate,
for the Deocutite in Christ,
and for all the clergy and the people,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our country, the president,
and all those in public service,
and for our armed forces everywhere,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For the great and holy Church of Christ,
for our holy archdiocese,
for this holy metropolis,
for this city and parish,
for every city and land,
and for the faith of God.
who live in them, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For favorable weather, for an abundance
of the fruits of the earth and for peaceful times,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For those who travel by land, sea and air,
for the sick, the suffering, the captives,
and for their salvation,
Let us pray.
to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our deliverance from all affliction,
wrath, danger, and distress,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us,
and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
commemorating our most holy
pure, blessed, and glorious Lady the Theodocus
and ever-Virgin Mary, with all the saints,
let us commit ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
To you, O Lord.
For to you belong all glory, honour, and worship
to the Father and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Give thanks to the Lord and call upon his holy name.
God is the Lord and he revealed himself to us.
God bless you.
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.
Καλήθεια, ο Θεός και επέφανεν ημίν ευλογημένος ο ερχόμενος εν ονόματι Κυρίου.
Του λήθους φράγισθέντος υπό τον Ιουδαίον και στρατείο των φιλασσόντων το άχραντον σου σώμα,
Ανέστης τρίμερος σωτήρ
Δωρούμενος το κόσμο την ζωή
Δια τούτο ελεύθερος
Στον ουρανόν ευών συζωδότα, δόξα τυ Αναστάσι Σου Χριστέ, δόξα τυ Βασιλεία Σου, δόξα τυ Οικονομία Σου, μονε φιλάνθρωπε.
Ω ξαπατρί και ιό και αγιοπνεύματι
εν σιμήτερα κρυβά
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Ως Ια Μαρία, το Πνεύμα σου.
Και νυν καία οικέης τους αιώνας των αιώνων, αμήν,
ο δημάς γεννηθείς εκ παρθένο και σταυροσίν, υπομείνας αγάθε.
Ο θανάτο των θανάτων σκυλεύσας και γερσιν δείξας ως Θεός,
Μη παρήδησους έπλασες
Σας τη χείρη σου, δείξον την φιλανθρωπίαν σου ελεήμον, δέξε την δεκούσαν σε Θεοτόκον, πρεσβεύουσαν οι περιμόν.
και σώσον σωτήριμον λαόν απέγνωσμένο.
Again and again in peace let us pray to the Lord
Lord have mercy
Help us, save us, have mercy on us
And protect us, O God, by your grace
Lord have mercy
Remembering our all-holy, immaculate, most blessed and glorious
Lady the Theotokos and ever-Virgin Mary
with all the saints.
Let us come.
and ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
To you, O Lord.
For yours is the dominion
and yours is the kingdom
and the power and the glory
of the Father and the Son
and the Holy Spirit
now and forever
and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Χωρί του Άδου σις συνήγυρας, τους απεών ωςτανώντας ως μόνος φιλάνθρωπος.
Εν είν και αϊκέ εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν,
ου Γαβριήλ φεγγζαμένους η παρθένε το χαίρε,
συν τη φωνίες αρκουτό τον όλον δεσπότης.
Ευχαριστώ.
Συνήθεια, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κι εσπρος το μνήμα παρεγένον το ορθριε και αγγελικίν οπτασίαν θεασάμενε τρεμον.
Ο τάφος εξίστραπτε ζωήν, το θαύμα κατέπληντε ναυτάς.
Δια τούτο απελθούσε τις μαθητές, ε κύριτον την αιγερσήν.
Τον άδειν
Αν εσκύλευσε Χριστός ως μόνος κρατέος και δυνατός
και φταρέντας συνήγηρε πάντας
τον της κατακρίσεως φόβων λύσας δυνάμει σταυρού.
Ω ξαπατρί και ιό και αγιο πνευματί
εν το σταυρό προσιλωθείς η ζωή των απάντων
Και νεκριμένοι
ο αθάνατος Κυρίος, ανέστης τριήμερος σωτήρ και η γύρας Αδάμ εκ της χώρας,
διά του το εδυνάμις των ουράνων εβών συζωδότα.
Βόξα της εισπέθημας η Χριστέ,
Βόξα τη Αναστάση σου,
Βόξα τη συγκαταβάση σου.
Μόνε φιλάντροπε.
Και νυν καί αικαίς τους αιώνας των αιώνων αμήν,
Μαρία των Σεπτών του Δεσπότου Δοχείων,
Ανάστησον ημάς πεπτοκότας εις χάος,
δίνεις από γνώσεως σκεπτεσμάτων και θλίψεων,
Συγκριμένο.
Υπέφυγκας αμαρτωλών σωτηρίαν και βοήθεια και κρατέα προστασία και σώζεις τους δούλους σου.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδάξω με τα δικαιωμάτά σου,
Των αγγέλων ο Δήμος κάτε πλάγι ορών σε, ενεκρής λόγις Θεέ.
του θάνατου δε σωτήρ την ισχύν καθελώντα,
και συνδεαυτό τον Αδάμ εγύραντα,
και εξάδου πάντας ελευθερώσαντα.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε, διδάξον με τα δικαιώματά σου,
τι τα μοίρα συμπαθώς της δάκρυσην,
όμως.
God said,
are you, O Lord, teach me your statutes
very early in the morning
the myrrh-bearing way.
were hastening to your tomb lamenting,
but the angel appeared to them and uttered
the time for lamentation has ended.
Weep no more.
Go announce the resurrection to the apostles.
Have loyed to.
to yourself, O girl, Savior.
They heard the voice of an angel
clearly speaking to them.
Why do you walk out of the dead
the world who lives for his God
he has risen from the cell?
Glory to the Father and the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
We bow down in worship
to the Father and his Son
Amen.
and the Holy Spirit,
the Holy Trinity, one essence.
And we cry aloud with the seraphim,
Holy, holy, holy are you, O Lord.
Both now and ever and to the ages of ages, amen.
Giving birth to the giver of life, O virgin,
you delivered Adam from sin,
and to Eve you have rendered.
joy in place of sorrow.
He who from you became incarnate,
God and man has directed to life
him who fell from it.
Hallelujah, hallelujah,
glory to you, O God.
hallelujah, glory to you, O God.
Hallelujah, hallelujah,
Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
Vox as ioth eos
Again and again in peace
Let us pray to the Lord
Lord have mercy
Help us, save us, have mercy on us
And protect us, O God, by your grace
Lord, have mercy.
Remembering our all-holy, immaculate, most blessed
and glorious Lady the Theotokos
and ever-Virgin Mary,
with all the saints, let us commend ourselves
and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
For blessed is your name and glorified is your kingdom.
Αμήν
Glory to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit, both now and ever, and to the ages of ages. Amen.
Through the Holy Spirit as to the Father and the Son
belong the other.
honor and glory.
Therefore let us sing a hymn
to the Trinity, the one and only ruler.
Having lifted me up to the mountains of your laws,
brighten me with virtues, O God, that I may praise you.
With your right hand embracing me, O Lord,
keep me safe and shelter me
so that the fire of sin not burn me.
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit
Now and ever, and unto the ages of ages, Amen
By the Holy Spirit all creation is renewed
And thus returns to its first state
For he is equal in power to the Father and the Logos
The Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit.
now and ever and unto the ages of ages.
Amen.
To the Holy Spirit, the honor, worship, glory, and dominion
that befit the Father and the Son should also be ascribed.
For the Trinity is one in nature, but not in persons.
Ninna nas thysome leghi Kyrios, thysomen sotirio,
parysiasomen afto.
Now I...
Now I will arise, says the Lord, I will establish them in salvation, I will declare it boldly.
Again and again in peace
Let us pray to the Lord
Lord, have mercy
Help us, save us, have mercy on us
And protect us, O God, by your grace
Lord, have mercy
Remembering our most holy, pure, blessed and glorious Lady Theodore
Thou goes an ever-Virgin Mary
with all the saints.
Let us command ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
For you are the King of peace
and the Saviour of our souls,
and to you we offer up glory to the Father
and the Son and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
You rose from the tomb in glory as God, and you raised the world along with you.
The human race extolled you as God, and as death was obliterated, O Master.
Now Adam dances, and Eve rejoices, freed from the bonds, and cries out,
O Christ, you have granted resurrection to all.
Let us extol as omnipotent God the one who rose on the third day,
for he smashed the gates of Hades, and he raised from their graves the dead from all time.
as he wished
he was seen by the myrrh-bearing women to whom first he exclaimed rejoice thus
saying declaring to his Apostles the joy is the only giver of life then the women
in good faith bring good news of the proof of the victory to the disciples
but Hades groans and death laments the world exalts and everyone celebrates O
Christ for you have granted resurrection to all you were once completely full of
fornication of all kinds but today you show yourself a bride of Christ through
repentance.
you imitated the Apostle's lifestyle.
With cross being your weapon,
you trampled demons.
Therefore, glorious St. Mary,
you have appeared as a bride
of the heaven's realm.
You have appeared as a bride
You of Christ and daughter,
now in song we praise you,
O Mary most renowned.
Accounted the Egyptians' nurseling,
but you fleeing all the
error, you were altogether offered
as a seedling precious
to the church. With self-control
and supplication, you practiced
asceticism beyond the measure of
human nature. Therefore, you were exalted
in Christ through the way of life
and practice. Glorious St. Mary,
you have appeared
as a bride of heaven's realm.
You have appeared as a bride
of heaven's realm.
Amen.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
and we will be able to give the Vassilis Demetri,
and we will be able to give the Son of God,
and we will be able to give these the miracles.
Establish your servants who extol you,
O Mother of God, for they have formed
a spiritual choir for you,
Thank you.
living and abandoned, found, and graciously in your divine glory,
give glorious crowns to them.
The
Oksati dinami sukirie.
Amazed was the universe by your divine magnificence.
You who were perpetually a virgin carried the heavenly God of all in your womb
and gave birth to the eternal Son who awards salvation to all who sing
hymns of praise.
to you.
Creator's stead, rather disdaining the threat of fire, they trampled it and joyfully they
sang, O supremely praised, and most exalted, Lord and God, of the fathers you are blessed.
!
Ο κόστης Θεοτόκου διε σώσατον, τότε μεν τυπουμένος, γυνδενεργούμενος,
Την οικουμένην άφασαν, άγιροι ψαλούσαν, τον Κύριο νυμνείτε τα έργα και υπεριψούτε εις πάντας τους αιώνα.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Σοφία οριθιακούς μεν το Αγιο Ευαγγελίου ηρήνη πάση.
Εκ του καδιου αν είναι Αγιο Ευαγγελίου το ανάγνωσμα προσχωμέν.
Δόξα Συ Κύριε, δόξα Συ.
Ούσεις οψίας τήμερα
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Και ανπεκρίθηθ ομάς και είπε αυτό, ο Κύριος μου και ο Θεός μου, λέγει αυτό Ιησούς, ότι εώρακάς με επίστευκας, μακάριοι οι μη δόντες και πιστεύσαντες.
Amen.
Have mercy on me, O God, according to your great mercy,
and according to the abundance of your compassion, blood of my transgressions.
Bless me clearly from my lawlessness, and cleanse me from my sin.
For I know my lawlessness and my sin is always before me.
Yet you only have I sinned and done evil in your sight,
that you may be justified in your words and overcome when you are just.
Behold, I was conceived in transgressions
and in sins my mother bore me.
Behold, you love truth.
You showed me the unknown and secret things of your wisdom.
You shall bring me this unhappy land
to all the unbeaten white and snow.
You shall make me hear joy and gladness.
The bones that were humbled shall greatly rejoice.
Turn your face from my sins
and blot out all my trans...
transgressions.
Create in me a clean heart
of God and renew a right spirit
within me. Do not
cast me away from your presence
and do not take your Holy
Spirit from me.
Restore to me the joy of your salvation
and uphold me with your guiding
spirit.
I will teach and
rest your ways and the ungodly
shall turn back to you.
Deliver me from blood guiltiness,
O God, the God of my salvation
and might be the most important thing.
tongue shall greatly rejoice
in your righteousness.
O Lord, you shall open my lips
and my mouth will declare your praise.
If you desire
a sacrifice and would give it,
you will have a place with all
burnt offerings.
A sacrifice to God is a broken
spirit, a broken and
humbled heart. God will
not despise.
Do good, O Lord, in your good pleasure to
Zion and let the walls of Jerusalem
be built.
the new
and be pleased with the sacrifice of righteousness,
with offerings and comfort offerings.
Then shall they offer young bulls on your altar
and have mercy on me, O God.
May glory to the Father
and to the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
Open to me thy gates of repentance, O giver of life.
For early in the morning, my spirit hastens to your home.
Holy temple, bringing the temple of my body, all be filed.
But as one compassionate cleanses me, I pray, by your lovingkindness.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Συγχανίσου, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός
Όλο εκδαπανήσας,
Θεσ' έσπρεσβειες ρίξε μεν πάσης ακοθαρσί.
Ελέησον με ο Θεός κατά το μέγα ελαιό σου και κατά το πλήθος των οικειρμών σου, εξάλληψουν το ανώμημά μου.
Τα πλήγη
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
O God,
Save your people and bless your inheritance.
Look upon your world with mercy and compassion.
Raise the Orthodox Christians in glory
and send down upon us your rich mercies.
Through the intercessions of our all-immaculate Lady Theotokos
and ever-Virgin Mary,
by the power of the precious and life-giving cross,
the protection of the Honourable Heavenly Father.
in his powers,
the supplications of the honorable,
glorious prophet and forerunner,
John the Baptist,
the holy, glorious, and praiseworthy apostles,
our fathers among the saints,
the great hierarchs and ecumenical teachers,
Basil the Great, Gregory the Theologian,
and John Chrysostom,
Athanasius, Cyril, and John the Merciful,
patriarchs.
of Alexandrium,
Nicholas, Bishop of
Mira, Spiridon, Bishop of
Trimithus,
Nectarios of Pendapolis,
the Wonderworkers,
the Holy,
Glorious, Great Martyrs, George,
the Triumphant, Dimitrios,
the Merceimer,
Theodore the Soldier, and Theodore
the General Minas,
the Wonderworker,
Karalambo,
and Eleftherios,
of the high room.
martyrs, the holy,
glorious, and victorious
martyrs, the glorious, great
martyr, and all audible
Ephemiam, the holy
and glorious martyrs,
thekla, varvaranastasia,
Catherine, kiriakifotini,
marinam,
paraskevi, and Irene,
our venerable and God-bearing
fathers, the
holy and righteous ancestors
of God, Eoi, Kim and Anna,
our devout mother,
Mary
of Egypt, whose memory we celebrate today.
And of all your saints, we beseech you only, merciful
Lord. Hear us sinners who pray to you and have
mercy on us. Lord, have mercy.
Lord, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.
Thank you.
Kyrie eleison, kyrie eleison.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Through the mercy, compassion, and love for humankind,
of your only begotten Son, with whom you are blessed,
together with your all-holy, good-and-life-giving Spirit,
now and forever and to the age of God.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
In a via no aros, un del todo de gustas,
on los velos de la dignidad de la gracia.
He en regards a novedere, sin asfacere,
and beholden, beholden, a raise,
and so call these masses, greater in honor
than the spirit of his, and glory,
greater, and the unconfirmed, and the spirit of his,
Here we go.
!
Let us pray.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Amen.
We thank you, my Lord, for your love,
and the rest of the love, and the spirit,
the word, and the love, and the love,
and the love, and the love, and the love,
I love you.
Συμφανάζω αφόρυπο, σαρουτέχνε όλη νάτια,
Θεώ το Πόρος οδηγύτης, ευκαιρία, πιο πρόκειται.
Όχι, όχι, όχι, όχι.
Έθηκε την ελληνή του Κυρίου δευθώμε,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Συνήθεια.
I have practiced.
I think this is a good idea.
I have been hearing you.
to come Sunday.
Next slide.
Let's see.
Okay.
I like the way I'm going to go.
I'm going to go to the house.
Okay.
How are you?
Thank you.
.
Okay.
I'll step up here.
Step up to the workshop.
So I'm going to try to do this.
I'm going to sit here.
Okay.
Thank you.
Oh
Εν είτε Αυτόν πάντες οι άγγελοι Αυτού.
Εν ήρθε αυτόν, ας εδεινάς.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Praise God and His saints.
Praise Him in the firmament.
of his power.
You endured crucifixion
and you abolished death
and you rose from the dead.
We pray you grant us
a peaceful life for you.
Lord as the only
Almighty
was.
Thank you.
Αγήντε.
Υμνούμεν σε Χριστέ,
ετέχθης εκ Παρθένου
και αχωρίστος υπήρχες το Πάτρι.
Επαθές ως άνθρωπος.
Καίκουσιος υπέμεινας σταύρον,
ανέστης εκ του τάφου,
ως εκ Παστάδος προέ,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
It's your last day.
Thank you.
I'm going to sing.
Εν είτε αυθον εγκυβάλις ευυχής, εν είτε αυθον εγκυβάλις αλλα λαγμού,
Πασαπνοή εν εσάρτον τον Κύριον, σε μεν διεκόλειε της των τσεπτών εποπτείας, μόλις μον τον ούτε.
πρωτερών
το επισυρώμενον
μη αντήριον
η δεσίαισθησης
και των συθεώφρων
επραγμένων η συνείδησης
την προστακρήτωνα
συεπίστροφή
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
η κόνη γάρ προσβλέψα σα της ευλογημένης Θεοπέδος,
πάντων καταγνούσα τεσμάτων σου πανεύη με τον πριν,
εν παρυσία το θύμιον ξύλον προσεκίνησα.
I waited patiently for the Lord and he waited
And he heard my son, I waited
After he was a short-lived
The holy laugh and rejoicing
There in the gospel you received
The salvation of the Lord
For your own voices
I will never.
Thank you.
Καίσθηνε τα διάβηματά μου,
Τον σον παθόντας εικόνας, ευσεβός απείληψας, το Θεϊδέστα τον εξεικόνησμα.
εμψυχή γράψασα αρεπτόν ιδέες, και το σου τον υπερλεμψας, ως και της είδασας.
Κου φως επιβαίνειν της ίχνεσίν, καί γη θεν υπεραίρεσθε, εν τες προς Θεόν σου εν τεύξεσσι.
Καίνην παρησία πανέδοξε Μαρία το Χριστό, παρισταμένη δισόπινου.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Thank you.
Oh, yeah.
Grazie a tutti.
Thank you.
Amen.
Rav, I, I.
Both now and forever and unto the ages of ages,
You are supremely blessed, O Virgin Thessalonians.
For through him who from you became incarnate,
Hades has been captured,
and Adam has been called back.
The curse has been killed,
and Eve has been freed.
Thank you.
Death has been put to death,
and we have been brought back to life.
Therefore we extol him and cry out,
O Christ our God,
you are blessed,
for so was your good place.
Pleasure, glory to you.
Anahmes.
The Lord is the Son of God.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Πατ'ρ Παγκοκράτορ, Κύριε Ιερονογένες, Ιησού Χριστέ και Αγία Νέα.
Κύριε ο Θεός, ο Αγλός του Θεού, ο Υιός του Πατρός,
ο αίραν την αγαπία του κόσμου
πελέησον ημίδη
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Θεού πατρόσον η.
Κάθε κάστην ημέρα ανευραγίσωσε
και εν μέσω τ' όνομά σου
εις τον αιώνας
και εις τον αιώνα του αιώνος.
Καταξιώσον, Κύριε,
τ' ημέρα θα αυτήν
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Υπάρθη τους φυλακτήνε ημάς.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε ο Θεός των Παθέρω αν ημών,
και ενεχτών και δεδοσιασμένων
το όγδομά σου εις τους αιώνας αμήν.
Γέννη το κύριε, το έντεο σου εφίβας,
καθαπεριλθύσαμεν επίσθε. Ευλογητός η Κύριε, διδαξόμεν τα δικαιώματά σου.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε, διδαξό με τα δικαιώματα.
Τα δικαιώματά σου. Ευλογητώσ' ειμί, Κύριε, διδαξόν με τα δικαιώματά σου.
Κύριε, καταφύγει, εγενήθησ' ειμί, εν γενεά και εν γενεά.
Εγώ είπα, Κύριε, ελεήσω με
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Άγιος αθάνατος ελέης όνει μας.
Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος ισχύρος,
Δόξα πατρί και Υιό και Άγιον πνεύματι,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Μάτσος.
Σήμερον σωτηρία το κόσμο γεγόνε,
άσομεν το Αναστάθι εκτάμου,
και αρκικό της ζωής ημών.
Τα θεών γαρτών θανάτων,
Στον φάνατος
Blessed is the kingdom of the Father,
and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit,
now and forever
and to the end.
ages of ages.
Amen.
In peace let us pray to the
Lord.
Lord have mercy.
For the peace of
God and for the salvation
of our souls let us pray
to the Lord.
Lord have
mercy.
for peace in the
For the whole world, for the stability of the holy churches of God, and for the unity of all, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For this holy house and for those who enter it with faith, reverence, and the fear of God, let us pray to the Lord.
for our
Father and Archbishop Nicholas, the Honorable Presbyters, the Deacons in the service of Christ,
and all the clergy and people, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our country, the President, and all those in public service, let us pray to the Lord.
For this parish and city, for every city and country, and for the faithful who live in them, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For favorable weather and abundance of the fruits of the earth, and for peaceful times, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, amen.
Have mercy.
For travelers by land, sea and air,
for the sick, the suffering,
the captives, and for their salvation,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For our deliverance from all affliction,
wrath, danger, and distress,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, I am.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us, and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
Remembering our most holy, pure, blessed, and glorious Lady the Theotokos,
and ever-Virgin Mary with all the same.
Let us commit ourselves and one another
and our whole life to Christ our God.
To you, O Lord.
For to you belong all glory, honor, and worship
to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Αμήν.
Ευλόγει η ψυχή μου τον Κύριο και πάντα τα εντός μου,
το όνομα του Άγιου Νοθού.
Δες πρεσβίες της Θεοτόκου, σαν τερσώσαν ημάς.
Ευλόγει η ψυχή μου τον Κύριο και μη επιλανθάνου,
πάσα στα σανταποδόσεις αυτού.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Συγκέντρες του Θεοτόκου, Σεύβιορ, Σεύβορ, Σεύβορ.
Κύριος εν τ' ουρανώ, ειτίμασε τον χρόνον αυτού,
και η βασιλεία αυτού πάντων δεσκόζει.
Εσπέτσι βίηστης τελωτώ, σώτες όσα σαν ημά.
Εττικέθεια ειρήνη του Κυρίου δε ηθόμεν,
αν δηλαβούς όσων ελέησων και διαφυλακτούς και αλλήλως και πάσαν την ζωήν ημών,
Χριστό το Θεό παραθώμεθα.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Το κράτος και σου έστειν η βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα
του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Άγιου Πνεύματος
νυν και αη και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν.
Εν η ψυχή μου τον Κύριο, εν έσω Κύριον ερ τη ζωή μου,
σ' αλλό το Θεό μου έως υπάρχω.
Ωραία.
Σαν ημάσια Θεού, ο Αναστάσιακ νεκρός, σαν οντάσια, Αλληλούια.
Μακάριος σου ο Θεός, Ιακώβο, βοηθός αυτού, η ενπίσ' αυτού επί Κύριον των Θεών αυτού.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
και Αγίω Πνεύμα ετύ.
Κένη και αήν,
Θεής τους αιώνας των αιώνων, αμήν.
Ο Μονογεννησίος και Λόγος του Θεού
αθάνατος υπάρχον
και κατάδεξαμενος διάκτηνή
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Σαρκωθήνε εκ της Αγίας Θεοτόβου,
Καία Ιπαρθένιου Μαρίας, Απλέτος ενανθρωπής σας.
Σταυρωθείστε Χριστέ ο Θεός, Θανατό Θανατόν παρτίσας.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Again and again in peace let us pray to the Lord.
Lord.
have mercy.
Help us, save us,
have mercy on us, O God,
and protect us
by your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
Remembering our most holy,
pure, blessed, and glorious
Lady Theothokos,
and ever-Virgin Mary,
with all the saints,
let us commend ourselves
and one another
and our whole life
to Christ our God.
For you are Lord
For you are a good and loving God
And to you do we offer glory
To the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
Now and forever and to the ages of ages
Amen
Αυτή ημέρα είναι πίσεν ο Κύριος, αγαλιάζο μετά και εφρανθόμενε αυτοί.
Ουλίκους καγιστέντος υπό τον Ιουδαίον και στρατιώτων φιλάσσων.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Θείαρθη, δεύτε προσκυνησομεν και προσπέσομεν Χριστό,
σφραγισθέντος υπό των Ιουδαίων
και στρατείο των φιλασσόντων
το άχραντων σου σώμα
ανέστης τριμέρος σωτήρ
δωρουμένος το κόσμο την ζωήν
δια τούτο εδυνάμεις των ουρανών
Ευρώντσι.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
In giving birth you have preserved your virginity.
At your dormition you did not forsake the world, O Theodokos.
You passed over into life, Mother who has given birth to life.
And through your prayers of God
of intercession,
from that you have
redeemed our soul.
προφθασον ως αγαθή εις την βοήθειάν ημών τον πιστο σκραυγαζόντων σοι
ταχυνων εις πρεσβείαν και σπεύσον εις ηκεσίαν οι προστατεύουσα ειν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Let us pray to the Lord.
For you, our God, are holy, and to you we send up glory.
To the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit, now and forever, and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Holy God, holy mighty, holy immortal,
Lord of mercy on us, I need you.
Αγίος ο Θεός,
Αγίος Ισχυρός,
Αγίος ο Θανακός,
Ευχαριστώ.
Holy God, holy mighty, holy immortal.
Del
Mercy
Anah
The Lord is the Son of God.
Καθανατος εμπέρισον ημάς.
Ευλογημένος ο ερχόμενος ονόμι του Κύριου,
ευλογημένος η επιθρώνον δόξης εν τη βασιλείο σου,
καθήνα εσύ του βασιλείου,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Μα Θεός, Άγιος, Ισχυρός,
Let us be attentive.
Let your mercy, O Lord, be upon us.
Rejoice in the Lord, O ye righteous.
Wisdom.
The reading is from St. Paul's letter to the Hebrews.
Let us be attentive.
Brethren, when Christ appeared as a high priest
of the good things that have come,
then through the greater
more perfect tent, not made with hands that is not of his creation.
He entered once for all into the holy place, not taking the blood of goats and calves, but
his own blood, thus securing an eternal redemption.
For if the sprinkling of defiled persons with the blood of goats and bulls with the ashes
have first sanctified for the purification of the flesh, how much more shall the blood
of Christ who through eternal spirit offered himself without blemish to God
Purify your conscience from dead works to serve the living God.
Peace be to you, the reader.
Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia.
wisdom arise let us hear the holy gospel
Peace be with all.
And to your spirit.
The reading is from the gospel according to St. Mark.
Let us be attentive.
Glory to you, O Lord.
Glory to you.
At that time, Jesus taking the twelve again,
he began to tell them what was to happen to him, saying,
Behold,
Behold, we are going up to Jerusalem, and the Son of Man will be delivered to the chief priests and the scribes,
and they will condemn him to death and deliver him to the Gentiles.
And they will mock him and spit upon him and scourge him and kill him, and after three days he will rise.
And James and John, the sons of Zephadi, came forward to him and said to him,
Teacher, we want you to do for us whatever we ask of you.
And he said to them, What do you want me to do for you?
And they said to him, Grant us to sit, one at your right hand and one at your left, in your glory.
But Jesus said to them, You do not know what you are asking.
Are you able to drink the cup that I drink, or to be baptized with the baptism with which I am baptized?
And they said to him, We are able.
And Jesus said, The cup that I drink you will drink,
and with the baptism with which I am baptized you will be baptized.
Thank you.
but to sit at my right hand or at my left is not mine to grant,
but it is for those for whom it has been prepared.
And when the ten heard it, they began to be indignant of James and John.
And Jesus called them to him and said to them,
You know that those who are supposed to rule over the Gentiles lord it over them,
and their great men exercise authority over them.
But it shall not be so among you.
But whoever would be great among you
must be your king.
servant, and whoever would be first among you must be slave of all.
For the Son of Man also came not to be served, but to serve, and to give his life as a ransom
for many.
Glory to you, O Lord.
Please be seated.
In the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit, Amen.
Well, I'm a very happy person this morning.
Why do you ask?
Thank you.
Father Tom has surprised us this morning and came into the altar.
Father Tom Michalos, who is
served with such distinction for so many years. And here praying before the altar and all of a
sudden having this slim figure pop into the altar from the corner of my eye. Whenever Father Tom is
in church, our altar is filled with joy. And I just wanted that to be conveyed to all of you who
are who are in the church as well when there's joy in the altar
there's joy in the church as well.
So I pray that you feel not just the joy of Father Tom,
but the joy of the Lord, right?
So we are at the fifth and last Sunday of Great and Holy Lent,
and it's a good idea for us to review where we came from
and where we are now.
So if you recall, we were introduced in the...
pre-Lenten season, at the beginning of February, the church was calling upon us to remember
the publican and the Pharisee, where through the scripture readings we were told,
we were told how essential prayer, proper and appropriate prayer, and humility are.
and then the next Sunday we heard the parable of the Protestant.
son, where we learn of a father having two sons, the one son always obedient to the father,
the other, the prodigal, had gone off and wasted his inheritance on loose living, repents,
and he comes back.
And the whole theme of that Sunday was repentance, to change the way we think, the way we do,
a changing of our heart.
so it's not
always oriented toward the self, but that it is turned toward God, which is what repentance really
means. Because we're so accustomed to be living a self-centered, a self-focused life,
and the church is here teaching us that we should not be the center of our life because we'll only
live to disappoint ourselves,
but that Christ
needs to be the center of our life.
And so repentance means a turning of oneself to Christ.
It's not just what I want, but what is it that God expects of me.
And to live one's life under those terms, those conditions.
And then on the following pre-Lent and Sunday, we heard of the last judgment.
We're reminded that we will all be held accountable for the things that we think, say, and do.
and primarily how we treat one another.
It doesn't surprise me.
Well, somewhat it did when I first learned this.
We all know the Ten Commandments.
Only four out of the Ten Commandments
have to do with our relationship with God.
The other six have to do with our relationship to one another,
which tells me that God is more concerned
with how we treat each other
All right.
than how we treat him.
So, in that gospel lesson
of the last judgment,
we heard Jesus tell us
the criteria that God will use to judge us.
I was hungry and you gave me food.
I was thirsty and you gave me a drink.
I was naked, you clothed me.
I was sick or in prison.
And you visited me and comforted me.
and
And the righteous asked, when did we see you in this condition and served you?
And Jesus said, inasmuch as you have done it to the least of these, your brethren, you did it to me.
And this was the criteria that God will use to judge us.
He won't judge us, well, I don't know how he's going to judge us, but it's not how many times you came to church.
or if you had perfect attendance in Sunday school.
I mean, it helps.
But what really matters is how we treat one another.
I was hungry and you gave me food.
I was sick and you visited me.
I was naked and you clothed me.
And Jesus is not just talking about
the nakedness of the body,
but to be naked spiritually.
me.
there is so much that the church gives to us to prepare us for the coming of Lent.
And then on the following Sunday, pre-Lenten Sunday, was the Forgiveness Sunday,
where we are told about the significance of forgiveness. We all have heard the Lord said,
in the measure that you forgive one another, I will forgive you. And that is critical for
Christians to understand this.
that you forgive others, I will forgive you. Again, that has to do with our relationship with
one another. And this the church emphatically proclaims, emphatically proclaims the forgiveness
of sins. And then the very next day we embark on the Lenten journey. And the first Sunday we came
to the first Sunday of Lent, the Sunday of Orthodoxy.
where we are commemorating the historical restoration of icons in the church.
But the church also reminds us of the present importance of that feast,
and that is the restoration of the image of God that is in all of us.
All of us are icons of Jesus Christ.
There is an icon just as our church's walls and ceilings are beautified with.
icons. Each and every one of us possesses the image of God within us. But because of our
indifference to God, because of the sins that we have committed, that image of God becomes distorted.
It's like a mosaic that has fallen and is broken into pieces. And it is through prayer and fasting
and repentance and all the things that the pre-Lenten Sunday...
showed us, introduced to us, and by God's grace, that mosaic, that beautiful icon of Christ that
is in us, gradually becomes restored. And then we come to the second Sunday of Lent,
St. Gregory Palamas, the great father among the fathers of the church who taught us about prayer,
about how through prayer
we can obtain and have access to the grace.
grace of God to the point that we would not only be able to see the uncreated light of God,
but that it would illumine us as well. Fascinating. And prayer, St. Gregory talked about prayer that
was not with words, but prayer that was silence.
St. Gregory talked about the importance of stillness of the mind, stillness of the heart.
Remember, if we are talking at the same time, we can't hear each other. We can't listen to each
other. Likewise, when we say our prayers, St. Gregory teaches us, after you have said what
you've said, be silent. Be still and let God, let God speak to you.
experience his presence, his overwhelming peace that is filled with grace.
And then we commemorated the following Sunday, the Sunday of the veneration of the Holy Cross.
The cross is that quintessential symbol of Christianity. It reminds us of God's
infinite power, power over death, because it was through the cross, his death.
on the cross, Jesus' death on the cross, that he was able to destroy death for us.
And through his death, resurrection, and promises resurrection to all of us.
The Holy Cross sits on the altar every day throughout the year. And there are just three
occasions during the church year that it is brought out in the midst of the people,
so that they may take courage and strength, that they may continue.
the rigors of the fast. Then last Sunday we commemorated St. John of the Ladder,
who wrote this beautiful work, The Ladder of Divine Ascent, of which Father Michael spoke
so beautifully last Sunday. He likened St. John of the Ladder, likened this journey through life
as really like climbing a ladder,
and every rung on the ladder is a...
a vice that needs to be overcome,
and a virtue to be attained.
30 rungs.
And once we get to the top,
we'll experience what the church knows as theoses.
That is, vision of God.
Vision of God.
As Jesus said in the Beatitudes,
blessed are the pure in heart,
for they shall see.
see God. And today in our church, on the last Sunday of Lent, we commemorate St. Mary of Egypt,
a woman who in her early life probably surpassed every other person that ever lived in a sinful
life. She was someone who left home and lived on the streets of Alexandria at the age of 12.
and
she was so consumed by lust. There are some authors that called her a prostitute, but she
wasn't a prostitute because she sought the pleasures of her flesh, of her body, and didn't
want any money for it. A prostitute does what she does because she gets paid and needs the money.
St. Mary of Egypt was plying her trade.
without getting paid. She didn't want to be paid. She did it purely for physical lust.
And when she heard, she was from Alexandria, Egypt, when she heard that there was a pilgrimage
to Jerusalem to see the Holy Cross of Christ that was going to be presented to all the faithful,
there was a pilgrimage. All these people boarded the ship in Alexandria and were on their way to
Jerusalem. Mary of Egypt also wanted
to board, but she had no money. So she essentially gave herself to the crew and passengers to do
with her what they pleased, just so she can go to Jerusalem. And when she arrived,
she followed the people to the church of the Holy Sepulchre. And when she wanted to go into the
church there was a force that was prohibiting her from entering.
church. No matter how much she tried, she couldn't enter the church. And off to the side,
she saw an icon of the Virgin Mary and the Christ child. And she fell on her knees and prayed to the
Virgin Mary. She repented. She goes, I promise I just want to come inside the church and see the
cross of our Savior. And if you permit me, I will dedicate my life to you.
After a short while, she rose and entered into the church,
was able to see the precious cross.
And immediately after leaving the church,
she went out into the Palestinian desert.
And she lived there for 47 years in the desert
without seeing a single soul.
Until one year in her 46th year,
she encountered a priest by the name of Father Zosimas.
who he couldn't believe seeing this emaciated, weather-beaten woman living in the desert.
And when he encountered her, he thought at first that she was a demon.
And then when he saw her do the sign of the cross, well, he knew she wasn't a demon.
So he approached, and then he didn't even realize that she was a woman.
and he fell on his feet and he fell on his knees.
and began asking this holy person to give her a blessing.
But she in turn fell on her feet and asked Father Zosimas for a blessing.
And so they had this dialogue.
Father Zosimas was amazed that she knew the scriptures by heart
without ever having read them,
without ever having heard the scripture.
scriptures. How is it that she was in the wilderness and that she was able to know about
Jesus Christ? She could quote the Psalms, she could quote the Old Testament prophets
and the New Testament. And clearly, Father Zosima said, what she could not read or did
not have access to read, this was told to her directly by God, and especially the Virgin Mary.
and
And so she told Father Zosimas to return in a year
and to bring with him Holy Communion
because she hadn't received Holy Communion in 47 years.
And she says, come on Holy Thursday.
And Father Zosimas does exactly what she says.
A year passes.
He goes, sees her, gives her Communion.
And then she told him to return again the next year.
and when Father Zosimas returns
he didn't even know her name. When he returned a year after, she had already died. And there was
an inscription in the sand that said, my name is Mary, I am from Egypt, and I died the day you gave
me Holy Communion. So she is honored in the Orthodox Church on the fifth Sunday of Lent,
reminding us, and on April 1st,
reminding us that no matter how sinful our life has been, there is always salvation,
redemption in Jesus Christ our Lord. Don't ever say to yourself, I am hopeless. I am helpless
or beyond redemption. I'm sure if Mary of Egypt were here right now, which in a way she is,
she would tell each and every one of you never lose hope in the great
salvation and the works that Jesus Christ does. He worked a miracle in her life and
he awaits to work a miracle in our own. Never lose hope. Never be overwhelmed by
the many or how great your sins. Move forward by the grace of God, by the
intercessions of this holy mother
Mary of Egypt
and for all
all the saints and the angelic hosts as our intercessors.
May God bless and always keep you strong in his grace.
Amen.
May we all please rise.
And grant that, always guarded by your power,
we may give glory to you,
the Father
and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever
and to the ages of ages.
No one bound by worldly desires and pleasures
is worthy to approach, draw near,
minister to you, the King of glory.
To serve you is great and awesome
even for the heavenly powers,
but because of your inner...
and immeasurable love for us.
You became man without alteration or change.
You have served as our high priest and as Lord of all
and have entrusted to us the celebration
of this liturgical sacrifice without the shedding of blood.
For you alone, Lord our God, rule over all things
in heaven and on earth.
You are seated on the throne of the cherubim,
the Lord of the seraphim and the King of Israel.
You alone are holy and dwell among your saints.
You alone are good and ready to hear.
Therefore, I implore you, look upon me,
are sinful and unworthy, sir.
and cleanse my soul and heart from evil consciousness.
Enable me by the power of your Holy Spirit,
so that vested with the grace of priesthood
I may stand before your holy table
and celebrate the mystery of your holy and pure body
and your precious blood.
To you I come with bowed head and pray.
Do not turn your face away from me
or reject me from among your children,
but make me your sinful and unworthy servant,
worthy to offer you these gifts.
For you, Christ our God, are the offer and the offered,
the one who receives and is destroyed.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια.
Είτε χερομυριστικώς οι κονίζοντες και τους οποίοι άδεικον γρυσάγιων ή ομπροσάδοντες.
Πάστε την βιωτική να ποθώ μεθαμέριναν, ως τον βασιλέα των όλων υποδεξόμενοι
τες αγγελικές αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια.
Ανάσταση, Χριστό, Θεα σαν να μας δώσουμε.
προσκυνήσουμεν Άγιον Κύριον Ιησούν τον μόνον αναμάρτητον
των Σταυρών Σου Χριστέ προσκυνούμεν και την Αγία Σου Ανάσταση
ενυνούμεν και δοξάζουμε. Συγκαρι Θεός ημών εκτός σου
όλου τον ομάζ σου ονομάζουμε. Βλέπετε πάντα Συπιστή
προσκυνήσουμε την του Χριστού Αγία Ανάσταση.
Η Βουγαρήλφια για τον Σταυρό χαρά με τον κόσμο
διαπαντώσουμε τον Βούλιο στον Κύριο
ενυνούμεν την Ανάσταση δεχνώ.
Αυτό το βόλμα είναι που μήνες τύριοι.
Θανά το θανά στον όλα εσένα.
Λέει σώμη ο Θεός και από το μέσος σου και από το πλήθος των εκτευμών σου εξάλιξε ο εντόν νόμημά μου.
Επι πλύον πύρομαι από της ανομίας μου και από της αμαρτίας μου καθαρισώνα.
Ό,τι την ανομία μου οικογενός σου και η αγιαμαρτή μου ονοποιώνει ο ίσκης για παντός.
Σήμανον ήμαρτον και τα πανερόν ονοποιών σου εγκλείσα, όπως αντικαίωθείς σαν τις λόγες σου και νικήσεις από κοινές θέσεις.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Σας ευχαριστώ, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή, Καλή
Από όλους με τη μεγαλία στους οδηγείους.
Αν αδελφέ και στους ευθύνσοντας, αδελφέ, σύγχωρισόντας,
αδελφέ, σύγχωρισόντας, αδελφέ, σύγχωρισόντας, αδελφέ, σύγχωρισόντας,
σταγόντα και δεύχει δετροχήλια.
Ανεύει ο Θεός εν αλλαλαγμού Κύριος εν φωνής αλπιγός.
The Lord is the Son of God.
Αμήν.
En di Vasioli afto panto te din kiaia,
kia istus aeonas ton aeono.
Amen.
May the Lord our God
I'm going to go.
Remember us all in his kingdom, both now and forever, and to the ages of ages.
Thank you.
Είσαι ομιστή Κυρίως ο Θεός, για τη βασιλεία αυτού πάντου.
Βλέσαν και δικές αόρων,
δορυφορούμενον,
τάξε σύν,
Ωραία!
Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia.
Let us complete our prayer to the Lord.
Lord have mercy.
For the precious gifts here presented, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For this holy house and for those who enter it,
with faith, reverence, and the fear of God,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
for our deliverance from all affliction.
wrath, danger, and distress,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us,
and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
For a perfect, holy, peaceful, and sinless day,
let us ask the Lord.
Bravo!
Grant this, O Lord.
An angel of peace, a faithful guide, a guardian of souls and bodies, let us ask the Lord.
For forgiveness and remission of our sins and offenses, let us ask the Lord.
And this shall not be
For all that is good and beneficial to our souls, and for peace in the world, let us ask the Lord.
For the completion of our lives in peace and repentant, let us ask the Lord.
Glad this, O Lord.
Christian and to our lives,
peaceful without shame and suffering,
and for a good defense
before the awesome judgment seat of Christ.
Rang this, O Lord.
Remembering our most holy, pure,
blessed and glorious Lady Theotokos,
and ever-Virgin Mary with all the saints,
Let us commend ourselves and one another.
and our whole life, the Christ our God.
To you, our Lord.
Amen.
Irenipasi, peace be with you all.
Let us love one another that with one mind we may confess.
God bless you.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Τα στήρας, τα στήρας εν σοφία πρόσχομαι
Πιστεύω εις έναν Θεόν, Πατέρα Παντοκράτορα,
Ποιητή ουρανού και γης ορατώνται πάντων και αοράτων
και εις έναν Κύριο Ιησού Χριστόν,
τον Υιόν του Θεού τον Μονογενή,
τον εκ του Πατρός γεννηθέντα προπάντων των αιώνων.
Φως εκ φωτός, Θεών αληθινών,
εκ Θεού αληθινού γεννηθέντα ουπηθέντα,
Ομοούσιον το πατρί διού τα πάντα γένετο, των δημάστους ανθρώπους και δια την ημετέραν σωτηρίαν,
κατελθόντα εκ των ουρανών και σαρκωθέντα εκ Πνεύματος Αγίου και Μαρίας της Παρθένου και ανανθρωπίσαντα.
Σταυρωθέντατε υπερημόν επιποντίου πυλάτου και παθόντα και ταφέντα και αναστάντα την τρίτη μέρα κατά της γραφάς
και ανελθώντας στους ουρανούς και καθεζόμενος εν δεξιάν του πατρός
και πάλιν ερχόμενος με τα δόξης, κρίνε ζώντας και νεκρούς,
ούτης βασιλείας σου και αστετέλος.
εις το Πνεύμα, το Άγιον, το Κύριον, το Ζωπιόν, το Εκ του Πατρός εκπορευόμενον,
το Συμπατρή και Υιός συμπροσκυνούμενο και συνδοξαζόμενον το Λαλή σανδιά των προφητών.
Εις μίαν Αγίαν Καθολικήν και Αποστολικήν Εκκλησία,
ομολογώ εν βάφτισμα εις άφησιν αμαρτιών, προσδοκώ Ανάσταση νεκρών
και ζωήν του μέλλοντος αιώνος. Αμήν.
I believe in one God, Father Almighty, Creator of Heaven and Earth,
is Christ the only begotten Son of God begotten of the Father before all ages
light of light true God of true God begotten not created of one essence with
the Father through whom all things were made for us men and our salvation came
down from heaven and was incarnate of the Holy Spirit and of the Virgin Mary
and became man he was crucified for us under Pontius Pilate and suffered and
was buried and he rose on the third day according to the scriptures.
He ascended into heaven and is seated at the right hand of the Father, and will come again with glory to judge the living and the dead.
His kingdom shall have no end.
And in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the creator of life, who proceeds from the Father, who together with the Father and the Son is worshipped and glorified,
who spoke through the prophets, and in one holy, catholic, and apostolic church, I confess one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.
I look for the resume.
of the dead and the life
of the ages to come.
Amen.
Let us stand well.
Let us stand in awe.
Let us be attentive
that we
may present
the holy offering in peace.
A mercy
of peace
of sacrifice
of praise
The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ
and the love of God the Father
and the communion of the Holy Spirit
be with you all.
And with your Spirit
let us lift up our hearts.
We have lifted them up to the Lord.
Let us give you the word.
thanks to the Lord.
It is
proper and
right.
Singing the victory hymn,
proclaiming,
crying out, and
saying,
Holy,
Lord
of
Evangelicals,
ever
Thank you.
and earth are filled with your glory.
Hosanna in the highest.
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.
Oh
He gave it to his holy disciples and apostles, saying,
Take, eat, this is my body, which is broken for you for the forgiveness of sins.
Likewise, he took the cup of the fruit of the vine, and having mingled it, offering thanks, blessing, and sanctifying it.
He gave it to his holy disciples and apostles, saying,
Drink of this, all of you.
This is my blood of the new covenant,
shed for you and for many
for the forgiveness of sins.
Do this in remembrance of me,
for as often as you eat this bread and drink this cup,
You proclaim my death.
and you confess my resurrection.
Therefore, Master, we also,
remembering his saving passion and life-giving cross,
his three-day burial and resurrection from the dead,
his ascension into heaven,
and enthronement at your right hand,
God and Father,
and his glorious and awesome second coming.
Katapanda Kedhiapanda
We offer to you these gifts
from your own gifts
in all and for all.
Therefore, most holy Master,
we also your sinful and unworthy servants
whom you have made worthy to serve at your holy altar
not because of our own righteousness,
for we have
anything you look on the earth.
But because of your mercy and compassion
which you have so richly poured upon us,
we dare to approach your holy altar
and bring forth the symbols of the Holy Body
and God of your Christ.
We pray to you and call upon you, O Holy of Holies,
that by the favor of your goodness,
your Holy Spirit may come upon us
and upon these gifts you have presented
to bless, sanctify, and make this bread
to be the precious honor of our Lord
and God and Savior, Jesus Christ.
And this cup to be the precious blood of our Lord and God and Saviour Jesus Christ.
Shed for the life and salvation of the world.
of the Lord.
Εξαιρέτω ως της Παναγίας Αχράτου υπερευλογημένης εν δόξου,
δεσπίνης ημών Θεοτόκου και αϊπαρθένου Μαρίας.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αγίας Μαρίας της Αγυπτίας, Ίσκοθηνή, μεταλλούμε και πάντων, σωθήν ο Θεός,
και εμείς και πάντων τόν πρόκειται ημένα, τον Κύριο Αναστάσου, Ήσαι αγύα,
τον Δούλο του Θεού, Τιμοθέο Αρχιερέος, Διακώβο Αρχιερέος,
Ευσταθείο Γερμονάκο, Χριστουδούλο Γερμονάκο, Δημητρίο Ιερέος, Δημητρίο Ιερέος,
Καθήσελονικές Παρθενικές Παρθενικές.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
...
Let thy people
never
grant them rest, our God,
with the light of your countenance.
May we pray to you, be mindful of your heart.
Στος ασύ, εις.
Εμπρωτισμνήστητη Κύριε του Πατρός και Μητροπολίτου ημών Νικολάου,
ον χάρισε τις Αγίες Σου εκκλησίες εν ειρήνη, σ' ον έντιμον υγεία μακροημένη.
and worthy of the truth of the truth and of the truth.
And the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, and the Lord,
and the Lord, and the Lord.
And the Lord, and the Lord, and the Lord,
and the Lord, and the Lord, and the Holy Spirit, now and forever.
and the Lord, and the Lord, and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever.
and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
The mercy of our great God and Savior,
Jesus Christ, be with you all.
And with your spirit.
Having remembered all the saints
again and again in peace,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord have mercy.
for the precious gifts offered and consecrated.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
That our loving God, who has received them
at his holy heavenly and spiritual altar
as an offering of spiritual fragrance,
may in return send down upon us divine grace
and the gift of the Holy Spirit.
Let us pray.
Lord have mercy
Having prayed for the unity of the faith
and the communion of the Holy Spirit
let us commit ourselves and one another
and our whole lives to Christ our God
To you, O Lord
and
the
Lord
δέσποτα μεταβαρήσειας ακατακρήτος,
τολμάν επικαλείσθεσαι τον απουράνιον Θεόν,
Πατέρα και λέγει.
Πατέρι μόν, ο εμπίς ουρανής,
αγιασύγειο το θόλμα σου,
ευθέτω η βασιλία σου,
γεννηθείτε το θέλημά σου,
ως εγχανών και εχθυσγείς,
τον άρτο νημά του επί ουσιον,
Θα συμβείς και εγώ.
Our Father, Lord and Father,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those who trespass against us
in these non-filtations,
but who live us to meet us.
For thine is the kingdom, the power, and the glory of the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Πρόσχομαι τα Άγια της Αγής.
Οι δημιμένοι ζέσεις τον Αγίος του Πατωπηρήνθη,
ο Ιωρίς τους εύρυνες των αιώνων αμήν.
Ζέσεις πίστεως πύρις Πνεύματος Αγίου.
Πιστεύω Κύριε και ομολογώ ότι εσύ αληθώσω Χριστός,
ο Ιός του Θεού, το ζώντος ο ηθόνης των κόσμων,
αμαρτωρούς όσαι, ον πρώτος είμαι εγώ.
Ωραία.
Πιστεύω ότι τούτο αιστεί το άχροντον σώμα σου και τούτο αυτοαιστεί το κειμενά μας σου.
Βέβαιο μέλλον σου λέει η σώμη και συγχωρισώ με τα παρακτώματα,
τα εκούσια τα ακούσια, τα ειλόγω, τα ενέργω, τα ενλούς πλαγή,
για σώσ' όμουν κατακρύτες τα αφασχή των αφράγντους σου,
εις τη γενισάξη των αφιών και η ζωήν αιώνιων. Αμήν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
being gone on the flesh and the flesh
of all the angels
in your love O Lord cleanse my soul and save
loving Master and Lord Jesus Christ
my God let not be so who gives me
to my condemnation because of my unworthiness
but for the cleansing and sanctification
of soul and body and the pledge of the future
life and kingdom
it is good for me to cling to God and to praise him
the hope of my salvation
The Lord is the Son of God, and the Lord is the Son of God, and the Lord is the Son of God, and the Son of God is the Son of God.
Καίσθηκε το Κύπριο
Αδερφοί και στους γεσίους, ο γρανός του γρανού,
της μισούσιν κι αγαπώσιν εμάς ο Θεός συγχώρησε ο μακρός.
Παραγωγή, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί, παιδί,
See, be, be, be, be,
Praise the Lord.
Amen.
Praise God.
Venite, ton, Kyrie, oh.
Oh
O
Each thing, each thing.
Praise the Lord.
From the head.
Praise Him in the power of my land.
Amen.
As we announce each Sunday,
we invite our Sunday school children and teachers
to receive Holy Communion first,
that they may dismiss to their classes
after our Sunday school.
And teachers have received Holy Communion,
and we'll invite our faithful to come by row.
Thank you.
with the fear of God, with faith, and with love drawn near.
Ong de Paraná,
Thank you.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Christi timo vespo ta,
en divasi mi asu.
Christ is the Lord.
Othanae
O Son of God, as partaker of your mystical suffering,
For I will not speak
of your mysteries to your enemies.
Neither will I give you a kiss as did you die.
But like the thief will I confess you.
Remember me, O Lord, in your kingdom.
God, remember...
Remember me, O Master, in your kingdom.
Remember me, O Holy One, in your King.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Σώσον ο Θεός των λαών σου και βλογήσον την κληρονομία σου.
Save, O God, your people and bless your inheritance.
Υψόθητη από τους ορομούς ο Θεός και την πάση
θα γίνει δόξα του Ινού.
Υψώθηκε από τους ουρανούς ο Θεός και επιπάσαι την γινή δόξα σου.
Εύλογητός ο Θεός ημών.
Let us be attentive, having partaken of the divine, holy, pure, immortal, heavenly life, giving in awesome mysteries of Christ.
Let us worthily give thanks to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us.
Save us, have mercy on us, and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Lord, have mercy.
Having prayed for a perfect, holy, peaceful, and sinless day,
let us commit ourselves and one another and our whole life to Christ our God.
For you are our sanctification,
and here we give
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Ανταβαίνον έξου το πατρός των φώτων.
Κι εσύ την δόξαν και ευχαριστιαν και προσκυνήσιν αναπέμπομεν
το πατρί και το αιώ και το άγιο πνεύματι
νυν και αι και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Blessed be the name of the Lord from this time forth and unto the ages.
Ευλογητός η Κύριε διδαξον με τα δικαιωμάτά σου,
τον Αγίον ο χορός ευρεπηγήν της ζωής και έθυραν παραδείσου,
ευρωκαγώ την οδονδιά της μετανοίας, το απολολό σπρώβα τον εγώ ημι,
ανεκάλεσε με σωτήρ και σώσον με.
Ευχαριστώ.
are you, O Lord, teach me
your statutes. Give
rest, O God, unto
your servants and
place them in paradise
where the choirs of
the saints and the righteous
will shine as the stars
of heaven.
To your departed servants
give rest, O Lord,
overlooking their offenses.
Doxa,
Patry, keio,
and the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit of the Holy Spirit.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Amen.
Rejoice, gracious lady,
who for the salvation of all
gave birth to God in the flesh,
and through whom the human race
has found salvation.
Through you, pure and blessed Theotokos,
may we find paradise.
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia.
Glory to you, O God.
Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, δόξα σοι ο Θεός.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αναπαύσον Χριστέ, τας ψυχάς των δούλων σου,
ενθαουκέστη ο νοσ.
Ulippi ustenagmos
Albasoi arthelectitos
Among the spirits of the righteous perfected in faith,
Give me a second.
rest, O Savior, to
the souls of your servants.
Bestow upon them
the blessed life which
is from you, O loving One.
Glory to the
Father and the Son and the
Well,
Holy Spirit,
you are our God
who descended into Hades
and loosened the pains
of those who were chained there.
Grant rest to the souls
of your servants.
have mercy on us, O God, according to your great mercy.
We pray you hear us and have mercy.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
Again, we pray for the repose of the departed servants of God fallen asleep
and for the forgiveness of their every transgression.
both voluntary and involuntary.
Lord, have mercy.
May the Lord God place their souls
where the righteous repose.
Let us ask for the mercies of God,
the kingdom of the heavens,
and the forgiveness of their sins from Christ,
our immortal King and our God.
Grant this, O Lord.
Let us pray to the Lord.
the Lord.
O God of
spirits and of all flesh, you have trampled
down death and have abolished the power of
the devil giving life to your world.
Give rest to the souls of
your departed servants.
Hippocrates, Thomas,
Panteleys, Nicolaus,
Iohannes, Apostolos,
Maria, Sotirios,
Georgios, Epstathia,
Alambros, Georgios,
D.V.C.
In a place of light, in a place of repose, in a place of refreshment, where there is no pain, sorrow, or suffering.
As a good and loving God, forgive every sin they have committed in thought, word, or deed, for there is no one who lives and is sinless.
you alone are without sin, your righteousness.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
and he is the Lord of the Lord.
Amen.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For you are the resurrection, the life,
and the repose of your departed servants,
O Christ our God.
And to you do we send up glory
together with your eternal Father
and your all-holy good and life-giving spirit.
and hold now and forever and to the end.
Αιώνια η μνήμη.
Αιωνία η μνήμη
Eonia in nimi
Eonia autonim nimi
I'm
Κύριε Βέησο
Ευλογία Κύριου και Έλειος έλθει αυτούθια χάρητη και φιλάνθρωπία
πάντοτε νυν και αοι και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν
Δόξα Συ Χριστέ ο Θεός, ελπίσιμον δόξα Συ
ο Αναστάς εκ νεκρών Χριστός ο Λιθινός Θεός ημον
της πρόσφασης.
της Παναχράων του και Παναμώμου Αγίας Αυτού Μητρός,
δυνάμει του Τημίου και Ζωπιού Σκαυρού,
προστασίας των Τημίων, υπορανίων θείων, δυνάμων ασωμάτων,
ηκαισίες του Τημίου Ανδόξου, προφήτων Προδρόμου και βαπτιστού Ιωάννου,
των Αγίων Ανδόξων και Πανεφήμαν Αποστόλων,
των Αγίων Ανδόξων και Καλενίκων Μαρτύρων,
των Οσίων και Θεοφόρων Πατέρων ημών,
των Αγίων και Δικαίων Θεοπατώρων Ιωακήμ Κιάννης, της Αγίας Οσίας Παρδιάς.
Please be seated.
And as a kindly reminder, we are passing two collection baskets.
The first is for stewardship donations or donations to the church.
the second trade.
that will be passed is for the iconography fund.
Amen.
MUZIEK
Was that Ginny Gazepas?
Yeah.
Yes.
In the flesh.
Good morning.
Well, it's still morning, right?
I think we have about eight minutes before it's afternoon.
And I vow never to keep you here past 12 o'clock.
So anyway, we have the following announcements to make.
that this coming Tuesday,
our Orthodox life will be at 7 p.m.,
and it will be a discussion
on the continuation of the doctrines
and teachings of the Orthodox Church.
We'll also have an opportunity
to entertain any questions
regarding Holy Week,
since Holy Week, believe it or not,
is fast approaching.
So, but please keep in mind that this Thursday at 6 p.m., for those of you who can make it,
we are going to be making the palm crosses.
All we ask that you bring a pair of scissors and a Lenten potluck dinner, a Lenten dish,
so that we can have excellent fellowship and prepare the palm crosses.
I think on average we make about 1,600 or 1,000.
700. So the more people we have, the faster we can get this done. And then on Friday,
this coming Friday at noon, our Goya is going to be meeting here at the church to prepare our
Easter baskets for our homebound parishioners. So we have roughly 80 people in our community
who are pretty much at home. They're unable to come to church. They do, however, participate
stayed with us on the live stream.
But we always want to keep connected with them.
And thanks to the valiant efforts of Vai Hadji Kosti and her outstanding volunteers,
our Goyans are going to be assembling Easter baskets.
And then next Saturday, after the Divine Liturgy, until 2 o'clock,
our volunteers will be making deliveries of those Easter baskets.
And again, next Sunday, on Palm Sunday, we'll be making those deliveries.
if you would like
to volunteer all you have to do is see by had you go see and think by are you
going to be in the hall okay so if anyone is interested in volunteering you
can see by if you don't know who by is you can see Olga and if you don't know
who Olga is you're in the wrong church right so after church today we are
assumption
Greek Dance Group is going to be selling Easter lambades candles for children. So they have been
working all week making these beautiful decorative candles for children to hold for the resurrection
service and on Easter Sunday. So if you'd like, take a look and see if there is one of the candles
decorated by our and proceeds for
our Greek dance program. And next Sunday, believe it or not, is Palm Sunday. And we are going to be
welcoming, I don't know how many of you have been following the figure skating or the Olympics last
month. Well, we are going to be honoring a parishioner of ours and her partner who participated
in the 2026 Winter Olympics in Milan.
Emilia Zingas and Vadim...
Kolesnik, parishioners of our church. They came in fourth place or fifth place in the world in the
Olympics in ice dancing, and they just competed yesterday, I believe, in Prague, where they
received the bronze medal in the world championship. So very impressive for this young
couple. We are going to be honoring them next week here at our church.
and presenting them to all of you. And we're looking forward very much to welcoming both
Emmy and Vadim to our church, welcoming them home, I should say. And you'll have plenty of
opportunity to congratulate them and meet them if you haven't. They're delightful, delightful people.
So those are the announcements. There's plenty more in the weekly bulletin.
Please be sure you get a copy before you leave.
On behalf of Father Michael Manos and Father Tom Michalos, who surprised us this morning,
I wish you all a blessed last week of Lent.
And God willing, next Saturday is a very special day.
It's the Saturday of Lazarus.
It's also a day that my family for the last 23 years have been hosting a breakfast,
a Lenten pancake breakfast for everybody who comes to church in memory of my mother,
of blessed memory.
We've been doing it for 23 years here.
We invite all of you to come for the Divine Liturgy
and then enjoy the hospitality.
My whole family will be here from Papu to grandchildren
and Yaya, I should mention.
So, afdah.
The blessings of our Lord God and Savior Jesus Christ
be with you and with your families.
Amen.
MUZIEK
ZANG EN MUZIEK
Amen.
so